start.com 2001-12-11

# MSN.com Privacy Statement

MSN Statement of Privacy

MSN is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This MSN Statement of Privacy applies to Microsoft's MSN family of Web sites and governs data collection and usage at all MSN sites and services. Please read the complete MSN Statement of Privacy below and also click the links following this paragraph to learn additional details about how some of MSN's sites and services protect your personal information.

MSN Internet Access Service |  MSN Explorer  |  MSN Hotmail   
---|---|---  
 MSN Auctions  |  MSN Calendar  |  MSN Chat and Web Communities   
 MSN Greetings  |  MSN eShop  |  MSN Gaming Zone   
 MSN Health  |  MSN Messenger  |  MSN Mobile   
 MSN Money  |  MSN Newsletters  |     
  
Other Microsoft services linked to from this Web site, [Microsoft Passport](http://www.passport.com/Consumer/PrivacyPolicy.asp?PPlcid=1033), [bCentral](http://www.bcentral.com/privacy.html) and [MSN Radio and Video](http://www.microsoft.com/isapi/redir.dll?prd=windows&sbp=mediaplayer&ar=home&sba=privacy&pver=7.0) have their own statements of privacy which can be viewed by clicking on the links.

This confirms that Microsoft and MSN are licensees of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this Web site has agreed to notify you of the following:

  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site.
  * Which organization is collecting the information.
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  * The kind of security procedures in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Microsoft's control.
  * How you can correct inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact [MSN Privacy](mailto:MSNPrivacy@msn.com) by clicking on the link. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe by emailing [www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with MSN to resolve your concerns.

Collection of your Personal Information

At some sites, MSN collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. At other sites, MSN collects anonymous demographic information, that is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites. Some sites collect a combination of the two types of information. Information collected at one MSN Web site may be shared within the MSN family of Web sites.

MSN does not associate sensitive data, such as your race, religion, or political affiliations, with personally identifiable information. MSN takes precautions to segregate any sensitive data you may provide on MSN sites and services that reference your race, religion, sexual orientation, ethnicity or political affiliations.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through MSN Chats, MSN Communities, or other public online forums, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: MSN does not read any of your private online communications. Your MSN Chat conversations, MSN Messenger messages, Hotmail e-mails, and MSN Internet Access e-mails are completely confidential.

MSN encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from MSN so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Microsoft is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Microsoft and MSN family of Web sites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by MSN and may be shared with other Web sites within the Microsoft family of web sites. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by MSN for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the MSN Web sites.

Use of your Personal Information

MSN Web sites and their operational service partners collect and use your personal information to operate MSN Web sites and deliver the services you have requested. MSN sites also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Microsoft and its affiliates. MSN may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

MSN does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. MSN may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, MSN may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Microsoft, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

MSN keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within MSN, in order to determine what MSN sites and services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within MSN to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

MSN Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Microsoft or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Microsoft, an MSN Web site; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Microsoft, its web sites, or the public.

Use of Cookies

Many of the MSN Web sites use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize MSN's pages, or register with MSN sites or services, a cookie helps MSN to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same MSN Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the MSN features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the MSN services or Web sites you visit.

Use of Web Beacons

MSN Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that allow MSN to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. MSN may include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or MSN Newsletters in order to count how many messages have been opened and acted upon. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information on the MSN network of sites and services; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about MSN Web site usage.

Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. MSN Web pages may also contain Web beacons placed there by our advertising partner, Avenue A, to help MSN determine the effectiveness of our Internet advertising campaigns.

Use of Third Party Ad Networks

The majority of the online banner advertisements you see on MSN Web sites are displayed by MSN.

In addition, MSN also allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to display advertisements on MSN Web sites. To do this, ad networks place a persistent cookie on your computer. Doing this allows the ad network to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. Microsoft does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third-party ad servers or ad networks.

MSN maintains relationships with a number of the third-party ad networks currently operating such as: 24/7 Media; AdForce; AdKnowledge; AppNet/admaximize/i33; Avenue A; BlueStreak.com; CFM&Z; Click Here; DoubleClick; Flycast; Interad Network; MatchLogic; Mediaplex; Sabela Media; The Thinking Media; and Vita Bella.

If you want to prevent one of these third-party companies from sending and reading cookies on your computer, you will need to visit each ad network's Web site individually and request that you be removed from its system.

Control your Personal Information

MSN offers its customers choices for the collection, use and sharing of personal information. You may go to the [MSN Communications Preferences](http://privacy.msn.com/choice/default.asp) page to proactively make choices about the use and sharing of your personal information. You may choose not to receive unsolicited marketing material from MSN Web sites and services or unsolicited marketing material on behalf of external third party business partners.

In addition, you may visit the ["MSN Personal Information Center"](http://privacy.msn.com/profilemgmt/) to view, edit or delete your personal information from the MSN database. Not all sites are represented at this time; additional MSN sites and services will be added to the Center in the future.

In both cases described above, you will be asked to make your requests while logged into a Microsoft Passport account, so that MSN can associate your preferences with a particular account. This security safeguard prevents someone else from making choices about the usage and control of your personal information. If you do not have a Microsoft Passport account, you can create one now by clicking [here](http://www.passport.com/).

You may also stop the delivery of future promotional e-mail from MSN Web sites by following the specific instructions in the e-mail you receive. The instructions explain how to stop receiving such e-mails.

There are some Web sites, including MSN Internet Access and MSN Hotmail, that send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service issues, product surveys, new feature announcements and news about MSN products and services. These e-mails are considered essential to the provision of the service you have requested. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered a part of the service you have chosen.

Security of your Personal Information

MSN secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. MSN secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites through the use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encrypted protection.

Protection of Children's Personal Information

MSN offers a Kids Passport account to allow parents to give consent for the collection, use and sharing of their children's (ages 12 and under) personal information online. To learn more about this service, visit Kids Passport on [www.passport.com](http:).

Changes to this Statement

MSN will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. When MSN posts changes to this Statement, you will see the word "updated" next to the Privacy Statement link on the front page of MSN. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how MSN will use your personally identifiable information, MSN will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. MSN encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Microsoft is protecting your information.

Enforcement of this Statement of Privacy

As a licensee of TRUSTe, and upholding our commitment to protecting the privacy of your personal information, Microsoft has agreed to disclose its information practices and to have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact MSN via [e-mail](mailto:MSNPrivacy@msn.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at [www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with MSN to resolve your concerns.

Contact Information

Microsoft welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Microsoft has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Microsoft by telephone, e-mail, or postal mail.

_MSN Privacy  
Microsoft Corporation  
One Microsoft Way  
Redmond, Washington 98052  
425-882-8080_

Click [here](mailto:MSNPrivacy@msn.com) to send e-mail.

Top

MSN Internet Access Service

What personal information is collected: When you register to subscribe to our MSN Internet Access service, MSN requests personally identifiable information such as your name, e-mail address, physical address, telephone number, credit card number, and in some instances, your social security number to register your account ("Registration information").

MSN may also automatically check the version of MSN Internet Access software and components you are using (including your browser version) every time you sign into MSN Internet Access service in order to optimize performance. MSN may also provide upgrades to such software that will be automatically downloaded to your computer.

How MSN uses your personal information: Your personally identifiable information may be gathered, processed or used in the following ways:

  * To service accounts, process, bill and collect payments pursuant to the MSN Internet Access Subscriber Agreement, and otherwise operate and deliver the MSN Internet Access service you have requested.
  * To support customer questions about subscription, billing, or use of the MSN Internet Access service.
  * To enforce any of the terms of the MSN Internet Access Subscriber Agreement.
  * To alert you of new products, product upgrades, special offers and other information related to Microsoft, MSN and the MSN Internet Access service.
  * To fulfill MSN Internet Access CD and other fulfillment request orders.
  * To create a Microsoft Passport account and an optional wallet account.

Who else may receive my MSN Internet Access registration information: By becoming a subscriber, you agree that Microsoft may share your personally identifiable information with third parties for their use in providing services to Microsoft in the course of operating and delivering the MSN Internet Access service, such as to process or collect payments, or provide customer support to MSN Internet Access accounts. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Microsoft, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

By becoming a subscriber, you also agree that MSN may present you with carefully selected third parties offers, unless you choose not to receive such offers by specifically changing your marketing [Communication Preferences](http://privacy.msn.com/choice/default.asp).

How do I access my personal information: Your information will be processed and stored by Microsoft in the United States, and, if you do not live in the United States, possibly in your country of residence. You may check and correct your information in your MSN Internet Access account in the "Help and Support" area of MSN Internet Access at [memberservices.msn.com/](http://memberservices.msn.com/). You may also contact MSN Internet Access Customer Service to determine whether such information has been accurately recorded, and, if not, to request correction of any inaccuracies. You can reach a live interactive online support representative 24 hours a day, 7 days a week at [msn.webhelp.com/msn/](http://msn.webhelp.com/msn/).

If your account was offered in conjunction with another company through a co-promotion, you will be notified upon registration about how to contact the other party in order to check and correct your information if necessary. In some cases, both MSN and the other company with whom you signed up for MSN Internet Access, will both receive your registration information.

How do I control my personal information: If you do not wish to receive any special offers on behalf of selected third party companies, or from MSN, access the [Communication Preferences](http://privacy.msn.com/choice/default.asp) section of the [MSN Privacy Statement](http://privacy.msn.com/choice/default.asp). Review the list of choices on the page and check the appropriate boxes. You will still receive communication from MSN Internet Access to alert you to new products, product upgrades, special offers and other information related directly to the MSN Internet Access service.

Top

MSN Explorer

What personal information is collected: When you sign up for MSN Explorer, we request registration information including personally identifiable information such as your name and address, as well as non-personally identifiable information including your occupation and other demographic information. Once registered, MSN will recognize you on your future visits to MSN Explorer. Through MSN Explorer registration, you have also created a Microsoft Passport account. For more information about Passport and the Passport services, go to [www.passport.com](http://www.passport.com/).

MSN Explorer gathers anonymous information, such as how many times a user attempts to log on, the average time for rendering the home page, or the length of time of your session online, while performing a continuous service quality monitoring function. MSN performs this service to help improve the technical quality of the service. The anonymous information does not contain any personally identifiable information.

MSN Explorer collects and stores your favorite Web page addresses (URLs) in your Favorites list on a secure MSN server. This allows you to have your Favorites available from whichever computer you use to access MSN Explorer, even if you use multiple computers. It synchronizes the list you are using with the list on the server so that you can add or delete Favorites from any computer running MSN Explorer, anywhere in the world. The sole purpose of storing the information on the server is to provide you with the convenience of having your Favorites available to you anywhere you use MSN Explorer. Your Favorites are not used by MSN for any purpose other than to provide you access to them.

Periodically, you may see a message informing you of a critical performance error in MSN Explorer. This message will ask you to send data to MSN. If you agree, MSN Explorer will automatically send and collect data needed to help MSN determine what caused the error. You may choose whether you want to send your data to help MSN learn why the error occurred. Before you choose to send your data to MSN, you will have an opportunity to review that data. If you choose to send the data, in certain instances, your personally identifiable information may also be sent to MSN. This personally identifiable information will be deleted prior to the review of the error data you send.

How MSN uses your information: MSN uses your registration information to authenticate you every time you sign in to MSN Explorer. MSN uses anonymous data gathered during service quality monitoring to improve the technical quality of the MSN Explorer service.

MSN Explorer will not disclose your Favorites list to other MSN sites or share this list with any third parties, except when required to do so by law as described above in the MSN Privacy Statement. MSN does not use your Favorites list to create profiles. Nor will you receive marketing materials as a result of storing your Favorites on MSN servers. When you delete an item from your Favorite it is deleted from MSN servers when you sign out of MSN Explorer.

MSN uses data gathered in error reporting to learn how to prevent future critical performance errors.

Who else may receive my personal information: All information you share with MSN Explorer is governed by the MSN Privacy Statement, except as noted above.

How do I control my personal information: You may change your personal information, at any time while you are online, by going to the MSN Explorer Member Services pages under "Help/Settings" at the top of the MSN Explorer home page.

Top

MSN Hotmail

What information is collected: Hotmail collects information during the registration process. The personally identifiable information Hotmail collects includes first and last name. In addition, Hotmail also collects non-personally identifiable information such as: country, region or state, zip or postal code, time zone, gender, birth date and occupation. You may update your Registration Information at any time from within your Hotmail account by clicking the "Options" button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Personal" icon.

How does MSN use my information: Your registration information is used to operate the site, for demographic statistics, and to display appropriate individualized advertisements. Hotmail will not send you any unsolicited information, including e-mail, except as mentioned below. New users will receive a Hotmail welcome letter explaining the features provided by the service. Hotmail may also send periodic member letters to announce important service changes, new features, technical issue updates and news about other Microsoft products and services. Hotmail may also contact you to conduct research about your opinion of current and prospective services via e-mail surveys. Hotmail may from time to time contact you, on behalf of external business partners, about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. Hotmail will not share your e-mail address with these business partners.

Who else may receive my personal information: Hotmail keeps your personally identifiable information private and does not share it with any third parties, unless you choose, at the time of registration, to be listed in either the Hotmail Directory or the Internet White Pages directory. In the case of the Internet White Pages, we will share your registered name, location, and e-mail address with the Internet White pages provider InfoSpace who may only use your personally identifiable information to provide their directory services. For more information about how to change you directory preferences, see the FAQ below. Hotmail will not disclose your Personal Information unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Microsoft; (3) enforce the MSN Hotmail Terms of Use; or (4) act to protect the interests of its members or others.

Your non-personally identifiable information from your Hotmail registration (such as zip code and gender) may be shared with other Microsoft websites to provide a more personalized advertising experience online. For example, you may see ads from a Microsoft bCentral/LinkExchange Banner Network member as you surf the Web but none of your personally identifiable information is shared with the third party websites.

What can I do to manage unsolicited e-mail in my Hotmail account? Hotmail will not sell, lease or rent its member lists with any third parties. While Microsoft continues to actively review and implement new technology, such as expanded filtering features, there is no currently available technology that will totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited e-mail. Using tools such as the Inbox Protector and being cautious about the sharing of your e-mail address while online will help reduce the amount of unsolicited e-mail you receive. For more information on how to best use Hotmail's tools, please contact abuse@hotmail.com.

How do I control my personal information: You may update your Registration Information at any time from within your Hotmail account by clicking the "Options" button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Personal" icon.

How can I change my preferences for the Hotmail Directory and Internet White Pages?

During the Hotmail registration process you are given the choice as to whether you want to be listed in the Hotmail Directory and the Internet White Pages. If you did not make a choice during the initial registration process, your registered name and location is listed in the Hotmail Directory and the Internet White Pages. At any time, you may remove your information from the Hotmail Directory by clicking on the "Options" button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Personal" icon. To remove your e-mail address from the Internet White Pages, go to www.msn.com,click on “More,” click on "White Pages", click on "Email Search" where you may register or delete your e-mail address.

If you have questions about our privacy policy, please e-mail [Hotmailprivacy@hotmail.com](mailto:Hotmailprivacy@hotmail.com).

Top

MSN Auctions

What information is collected: When you participate on the MSN Auctions site, MSN may request personally identifiable information such as your name or e-mail address as well as transactional information such as your credit card number or shipping address. You may go at any time to the My Account section to update your name, address and other personal information. You may also edit or change your preferred credit card at the Credit Information section of the site.

How does MSN use your personal information: MSN does not share any of your personally identifiable or transactional information with any person or entity other than FairMarket, MSN's service provider on MSN Auctions. FairMarket only uses this information to operate the MSN Auctions service and does not share it with any other parties. FairMarket may also use anonymous, aggregated data about popular listings and purchase patterns of MSN customers to improve the MSN Auctions service.

Who else may receive my Auctions information: No other third party receives your personally identifiable information or other transactional data except for those with whom you make auction transactions or other auction participants with whom you choose to share your information.

Top

MSN Calendar

When you register for MSN Calendar, MSN requests your first and last name, primary e-mail address and time zone. Your first and last names are used only for the "Invites" feature. This feature allows you to create an appointment and send an invitation for that appointment to another person by e-mail. The time zone is used to display your calendar correctly. Your primary e-mail address is used as the address where we send your appointment "reminders."

No information in your calendar date book is used in any other way by MSN Calendar or other MSN Web sites. Unless you choose to send an invitation to another person, no third party receives any of your calendar or other personally identifiable information.

MSN Calendar system administrators are the only people who have access to customer accounts and can only view customers account information to troubleshoot technical issues, upon your request for customer assistance.

Top

MSN Chat and Web Communities

To participate in MSN Chat and Web Communities, MSN requests that you create a social nickname, which is the name you will be known by to others in those public places. If you do not choose to create a social nickname, you will simply be identified as a "Guest."

At MSN Web Communities, MSN Chat, MSN Gaming Zone and Microsoft Passport, MSN gives you the opportunity to create a public profile of yourself. The public profile contains personal information - such as your hobbies and interests - that you have volunteered about yourself so that other participants in MSN chat rooms, MSN Web Communities or other public places can learn something about you. All such information is optional and everything you enter in your public profile will be visible to the public.

Your MSN social nickname and the information in your public profile is used by the MSN Chat, MSN Web Communities, MSN Gaming Zone, and Microsoft Passport Web sites to enhance your experience on those sites. None of this information is shared with any third parties. Your social nickname and public profile information are available and visible to other MSN visitors and customers using the site. MSN urges you to be careful only to enter information on your public profile that you are comfortable sharing with the public at large. You may change, edit or delete information about yourself from your public profile at any time while online by going to Public Profiles, Edit Your Public Profile. You may also select a different social nickname at any time.

While participating in chats, communities or other public forums, MSN cautions you against giving out personally identifiable information (such as names and addresses, phone numbers, social security numbers, credit card numbers, and driver's license numbers) to strangers online, which they may use for illegal or harmful purposes.

Top

MSN Greetings

MSN Greetings is provided by MSN's partner Egreetings Network, Inc. When you check the box on the MSN Greetings' send page to receive information from Egreetings Network, your e-mail address will be collected by Egreetings Network. When you register to use the Egreetings service on Egreetings.com and you submit your personal information (such as your name, gender, or age) on the registration form on Egreetings.com, this information will be supplied to Egreetings and is not transmitted to MSN. Note that you may send greeting cards on both MSN.com and Egreetings without registering. Both companies are committed to protecting your privacy. To determine how Egreetings Network will treat your personal information, please refer to its privacy policy at [www.egreetings.com](http://www.egreetings.com/).

Top

MSN eShop

What Information is Collected: MSN does not collect information associated with your purchase when you shop at one of the merchant Web sites linked to MSN Shopping. What you purchase is known only to the merchant. This remains true even if you are signed into a Microsoft Passport account while you are making the transaction. Be sure to read the participating merchant's privacy policy to better understand its use of your personal information.

When you purchase an MSN Gift Certificate, MSN requests your e-mail address, credit card information, and other information about you and the gift certificate recipient. That information is not shared with any third parties. Similarly, when you make an MSN Wish List, none of the information that you enter on your wish list is shared with third parties and is collected only for the customer's benefit.

Top

MSN Gaming Zone

To play on MSN Gaming Zone, we request that you create a social nickname which is the name you will be known by to others in public areas. The Gaming Zone also requests your e-mail address so that we may contact you if you are the winner of a competition and where we may send you an optional Gaming Zone newsletter.

Inside the Gaming Zone it is possible to create an optional personal profile. This profile contains information about the games you like to play, your favorite URL, a description of your interests, and scores you might have attained if you visited any of the rated rooms on the site. No information in your public profile is shared with any third party. You may edit, delete, or modify your personal profile at any time.

The Gaming Zone also hosts a small number of premium games. To participate in these optional games a fee is charged. In order to collect this fee, the Gaming Zone requests your credit card information sufficient to process the credit card transaction for this service.

Top

MSN Health

MSN Health is provided by MSN's partner, WebMD. WebMD requests personally identifiable information and other demographic data in three areas: registration, creation of a member profile, and in the MyHealthRecord section of the site. WebMD uses this information that you have volunteered to provide you with the health related services you have requested. WebMD will not release any of your personally identifiable information or associated health information to any third party without your permission. MSN does not collect or use any of this information.

You may change the information in your WebMD member profile at any time, or request that your information be deleted by e-mailing [support@webmd](mailto:support@webmd).

MSN encourages you to read the entire [MSN Health/WebMD Privacy Statement](http://content.health.msn.com/medcast_channel_toc/1761) to understand the extra precautions that WebMD has taken to safeguard your health data.

Top

MSN Messenger

When you sign up for MSN Messenger service, MSN requests your Passport Member Name, a "friendly" name that you choose, a phone number (optional), and the list of "buddies" with whom you can send and receive instant messages and similar information about those "buddies." No other company has access to your phone number or buddy information. Only authorized MSN customer service representatives may access this information, upon your request, to assist you in using the Messenger service. Go to Tools Options in Messenger to change your friendly name, phone number, or any other information.

Top

MSN Mobile

When you sign up for MSN Mobile for your mobile phone or pager, MSN requests your Passport Member Name, time zone, mobile e-mail address (usually phonenumber@carrier.com), carrier name, ZIP code, your phone or pager member ID, your phone or pager's gateway server name, and your mobile alert preferences. MSN uses this information to operate the MSN Mobile service and provide customer support to users when they need help. If you signed up for MSN Mobile at a co-branded site, your carrier will also have your personal information. MSN does not share your information with any third parties. You may visit the mobile.msn.com website at any time to edit or change your personal information.

Top

MSN Money

In accordance with the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act of 1999, annual privacy notices for MSN Money customers receiving financial services will be provided through the continual posting of the current version of this privacy statement in a clear and conspicuous manner on this Website. By using MSN Money services, you acknowledge receipt of this statement and agree to receive subsequent privacy notices in this manner on an on-going basis.

What information is collected: As part of providing MSN Money customers with a central location for managing personal finances, MSN may request that you furnish personally identifiable information such as your e-mail address, name and physical address along with financial data such as account balances, account numbers, credit card balances, and stock and bond portfolio information.

What MSN does with your information: MSN uses this information to provide you with online bill-paying services, portfolio tracking, and other requested financial services. MSN specifically does not share your financial data with any third parties except those who assist in providing the service you have requested. MSN requires these third parties to meet MSN standards for privacy and security. These third parties may not use your data for any purpose other than delivering the specific service you requested. MSN also may use your information to deliver specialized or custom content on the MSN network of sites and services.

Who else may receive your information: In aggregate form only, MSN may share demographic information about MSN Money customers with advertisers to enable them to deliver a customized ad while you are surfing on the MSN network. As a general matter, we will disclose personal information about you to other companies only with your consent. We may disclose such information to other companies when necessary to perform a transaction or provide a service that you have requested.

For more detailed information about privacy protection for MSN Money customers:

For more detailed information about how CheckFree handles your data for the MSN Bill Pay service, please read CheckFree's privacy statement at <http://moneycentral.msn.com/banking/Billpay.asp>.

For more specific information about how your data is handled by the MSN Money MyAccounts feature, please go to <http://moneycentral.msn.com/banking/accounts/welcome.asp>.

Top

MSN Newsletters

When you subscribe to an MSN Newsletter, MSN requests your e-mail address. MSN strongly urges you to also select a password to protect your privacy, however, this is optional. MSN uses your e-mail address to send you the newsletter(s) you have requested. MSN does not share its Newsletter subscribers' e-mail addresses with third parties except as required to deliver the service.

You may subscribe and unsubscribe to MSN Newsletters by going to [newsletters.msn.com](http://newsletters.msn.com/). By using a password when subscribing, you are securing your newsletter subscription account. In addition, each MSN newsletter you receive will have instructions on how to unsubscribe prominently mentioned in it.

By using a password when subscribing, you are securing your newsletter account. If you do not secure your account, others who know your e-mail address can view and modify your subscription choices.

Updated September 2001
